Barry Commoner Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Speeches and Writings File, 1959-1976 (Box 14-179)
  - Book file
    - Poverty of Power
      - Foreign editions, correspondence, 1975-1979 (Box 119)
      - Galleys, 1976, (2 folders) (Box 103)
      - Galleys, corrected, circa 1976, (4 folders) (Box 115)
      - Galley, corrected, 1976, (2 folders) (Box 118)
      - Galleys, 1976-1978 (Box 119)
      - German edition, 1977 (Box 117)
      - Letters received concerning Poverty of Power, 1976-1978 (Box 117)
      - Marie Rodell-Frances Collin, literary agency, 1975 (Box 119)
      - Memo, "Recent interest in public debate on basic economic issues," 1976 (Box 117)
      - New Yorker articles based on the book (Box 103)
        - Congressional Record reprint, 1976 (Box 119)
        - Copyright assignment, 1976 (Box 119)
        - Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 119)
        - Galleys, corrected, 1976, (2 folders) (Box 103)
        - Galleys, corrected, 1976 (Box 115)
        - Galleys, corrected, 1976, (3 folders) (Box 116)
        - Press release and published articles, 1976 (Box 119)
      - Permission to publish revised chapter 6, Friends of the Earth, 1978 (Box 111)
      - Radio interview transcript, "Kaleidoscope," WAMU, Washington, D.C., 1976 (Box 117)
      - Random House, 1977 (Box 117)
      - Research file for chapter 3, 1970-1975, (10 folders) (Box 114)
      - Reviews, 1976-1977, (2 folders) (Box 117)
      - Reviews, 1976 (Box 120)
      - Summary of The Poverty of Power by Arthur Palmer, undated (Box 117)
    - Science and Survival
      - Correspondence, 1966-1971, (3 folders) (Box 123)
      - Course outlines using Science and Survival, 1969, undated (Box 124)
      - Drafts, 1966, (5 folders) (Box 121)
      - Drafts, 1966, (9 folders) (Box 122)
      - Drafts, 1965-1966, (7 folders) (Box 125)
      - Drafts, book as submitted, 1966 (Box 123)
      - Drafts, Gollancz copy returned, 1966 (Box 124)
      - Foreign editions, 1968-1971, (9 folders) (Box 124)
      - Galley, 1966, (2 folders) (Box 123)
      - Jacket design, 1966 (Box 124)
      - Reviews, 1966-1970 (Box 124)
      - Title page, 1966 (Box 123)
      - Viking Press, 1966-1967 (Box 124)
  - Book series on pollution, project with Harcourt, Brace & World, 1969-1974, (3 folders) (Box 163)
  - Chronological file
    - circa 1940, 1954-1963, undated, articles and speaking engagements, (27 folders) (Box 14)
    - 1963-1964 "talk log" (Box 15)
    - 1964, Feb.-Dec., articles and speaking engagements, (12 folders) (Box 15)
    - 1965 "talk log" (Box 16)
    - 1965, Jan.-Oct. 1, articles and speaking engagements, (11 folders) (Box 16)
    - 1965, Oct. 22-Dec., articles and speaking engagements, (5 folders) (Box 17)
    - 1966 "talk log" (Box 18)
    - 1966, Jan.-Aug. 27, articles and speaking engagements, (9 folders) (Box 18)
    - 1966, Aug. 27-Dec., articles and speaking engagements, (8 folders) (Box 19)
    - 1967 "talk log" (Box 20)
    - 1967, Jan.-Apr. 21, articles and speaking engagements, (7 folders) (Box 20)
    - 1967, Apr. 24-July, articles and speaking engagements, (5 folders) (Box 21)
    - 1967, Sept.-Nov., articles and speaking engagements, (10 folders) (Box 22)
    - 1967, Dec., articles and speaking engagements, (6 folders) (Box 23)
    - 1968 "talk log" (Box 24)
    - 1968, Jan.-Mar., articles and speaking engagements, (8 folders) (Box 24)
    - 1968, Apr.-June, articles and speaking engagements, (10 folders) (Box 25)
    - 1968, July-Oct. 13, articles and speaking engagements, (7 folders) (Box 26)
    - 1968, Oct. 24-Dec. 26, articles and speaking engagements, (6 folders) (Box 27)
    - 1968, Dec. 28-Dec., no day, articles and speaking engagements, (4 folders) (Box 28)
    - 1969 "talk log" (Box 29)
    - 1969, Jan.-Mar. 4, articles and speaking engagements, (8 folders) (Box 29)
    - 1969, Mar. 16-May 12, articles and speaking engagements, (9 folders) (Box 30)
    - 1969, May 13-July, articles and speaking engagements, (10 folders) (Box 31)
    - 1969, Sept.-Nov. 7, articles and speaking engagements, (10 folders) (Box 32)
    - 1969, Nov. 10-Nov. 24, articles and speaking engagements, (6 folders) (Box 33)
    - 1969, Nov. 24-Dec., articles and speaking engagements, (4 folders) (Box 34)
    - 1970, binder for speaking engagements, (2 folders) (Box 34)
    - 1970 "talk log" (Box 35)
    - 1970, Jan.-Mar., articles and speaking engagements, (17 folders) (Box 35)
    - 1970, Apr.-May, articles and speaking engagements, (23 folders) (Box 36)
    - 1970, June-Sept., articles and speaking engagements, (19 folders) (Box 37)
    - 1970, Oct.-Dec., circa 1970, articles and speaking engagements, (15 folders) (Box 38)
    - 1971 "talk log" (Box 39)
    - 1971, Jan.-Apr., articles and speaking engagements, (21 folders) (Box 39)
    - 1971, May-July, articles and speaking engagements, (12 folders) (Box 40)
    - 1971, July-Oct., articles and speaking engagements, (11 folders) (Box 41)
    - 1971, Sept.-Nov. 11, articles and speaking engagements, (16 folders) (Box 42)
    - 1971, Nov.-Dec., articles and speaking engagements, (15 folders) (Box 43)
    - 1972 "talk logs" (Box 43)
    - 1972, travel expenses, (2 folders) (Box 43)
    - 1972, Jan. 3-16, articles and speaking engagements, (5 folders) (Box 43)
    - 1972, Jan. 17-May 1, articles and speaking engagements, (26 folders) (Box 44)
    - 1972, May 2-Dec., articles and speaking engagements, (28 folders) (Box 45)
    - 1973, Jan.-May, articles and speaking engagements, (28 folders) (Box 46)
    - 1973, June-Nov. 14, articles and speaking engagements, (23 folders) (Box 47)
    - 1973, Nov. 15-1974, Mar., articles and speaking engagements, (30 folders) (Box 48)
    - 1974, Apr.-Oct., articles and speaking engagements, (24 folders) (Box 49)
    - 1974, Nov.-1975, Apr. 22, articles and speaking engagements, (21 folders) (Box 50)
    - 1975, Apr. 22-Dec. 1, articles and speaking engagements, (19 folders) (Box 51)
    - 1975, Dec. 5-1976, Apr., articles and speaking engagements, (32 folders) (Box 52)
    - 1976, May-Sept. 17, articles and speaking engagements, (20 folders) (Box 53)
    - 1976, Sept. 18-Dec., articles and speaking engagements, (26 folders) (Box 54)
  - Drafts and correspondence concerning publications
    - 1967-1968, (11 folders) (Box 128)
    - 1967-1973, (21 folders) (Box 139)
    - 1967-1968, (8 folders) (Box 129)
    - 1968-1970, (15 folders) (Box 130)
    - 1968-1970, (18 folders) (Box 131)
    - 1969-1971, (25 folders) (Box 132)
    - 1969-1973, (17 folders) (Box 140)
    - 1971-1972, (12 folders) (Box 133)
    - 1971, (11 folders) (Box 134)
    - 1971-1973, (12 folders) (Box 135)
    - 1971-1972, (15 folders) (Box 136)
    - 1972-1973, (14 folders) (Box 137)
    - 1972, (9 folders) (Box 138)
    - 1972-1973, (11 folders) (Box 141)
    - 1973, (11 folders) (Box 142)
    - 1973-1975, (16 folders) (Box 144)
    - 1974, (10 folders) (Box 143)
    - 1974, (13 folders) (Box 145)
    - 1974-1975, (9 folders) (Box 146)
    - 1972-1976, undated, (16 folders) (Box 147)
    - 1975-1976, (10 folders) (Box 148)
    - 1976, (18 folders) (Box 149)
    - 1976, (5 folders) (Box 150)
    - 1976-1977, (12 folders) (Box 151)
    - 1976-1977, (10 folders) (Box 154)
    - 1977, (12 folders) (Box 152)
    - 1977, (12 folders) (Box 153)
    - 1977, (11 folders) (Box 155)
    - 1977, (9 folders) (Box 156)
    - 1978, (13 folders) (Box 157)
    - 1979, (11 folders) (Box 159)
  - Drafts by topic or title
    - Apollo space program, 1966-1968 (Box 167)
    - Biosphere, for Science Journal, 1969 (Box 167)
    - Audubon Society, 1969 (Box 167)
    - Bateson, Gregory, his "Theory of Action," undated (Box 167)
    - California environmental issues, undated (Box 167)
    - Civil defense and nuclear war, 1964-1966, undated (Box 167)
    - Civil defense and nuclear war, 1964-1966, undated, (3 folders) (Box 168)
    - Developing nations and ecological issues, 1968 (Box 168)
    - Earth Day, speeches, undated (Box 168)
    - Ecological problems related to public policy, 1969 (Box 168)
    - Ecosystem, UNESCO, undated, (2 folders) (Box 168)
    - Electron spin resonance, 1968, undated (Box 169)
    - "Environment" article, circa 1968 (Box 169)
    - Environment, technology, and public policy, proposal to the Twentieth Century Fund, circa 1971, (2 folders) (Box 169)
    - Environmental biology and the establishment of the Center for the Biology of Natural Systems, Saturday Review, 1966 (Box 169)
    - Environmental crisis (Box 169)
      - American Medical Association, 1967 (Box 169)
      - American Society of Newspaper Editors, 1970 (Box 169)
      - Dickinson College, Carlisle, Pa., 1970 (Box 169)
      - National Industrial Conference Board, 1966 (Box 169)
      - National Industrial Conference Board, 1966 (Box 170)
      - Scientists' Institute for Public Information, 1967 (Box 170)
      - TWA Magazine, 1970 (Box 170)
    - Environmental pollution, 1968 (Box 170)
    - Free radicals and electron spin resonance, 1963-1965, undated, (2 folders) (Box 170)
    - Free radicals in biology, 1948-1953 (Box 170)
    - Genetics (Box 170)
      - American Chemical Society, 1968 (Box 170)
      - Article drafts, 1962, undated (Box 170)
      - Article drafts, 1962, undated, (2 folders) (Box 171)
      - Biology teachers, 1967, undated (Box 171)
      - National Science Foundation application, 1967 (Box 171)
      - Watson-Crick, 1968 (Box 171)
    - Illinois Pollution Control Board, 1971, (2 folders) (Box 171)
    - "Integrity of Science," 1962-1964, undated, (2 folders) (Box 171)
    - "Integrity of Science," 1962-1964, undated, (2 folders) (Box 172)
    - Intellectual freedom, University of California, 1967 (Box 172)
    - "Is Biology a Molecular Science?" Bowdoin College, Brunswick, Maine, 1966 (Box 172)
    - "Is Science Getting Out of Hand?" 1963 (Box 172)
    - Lake Erie, 1967, (2 folders) (Box 172)
    - Medical school talk, 1968 (Box 172)
    - Miscellaneous, 1966-1970, undated, (3 folders) (Box 173)
    - Molecular biology, New School for Social Research, New York, N.Y., 1966-1967, (2 folders) (Box 173)
    - New currents and social issues in biology, 1960-1964, undated (Box 173)
    - Nitrogen cycle, 1971 (Box 173)
    - Nitrogen fertilizer, 1967, (2 folders) (Box 173)
    - Nitrogen fertilizer, 1971, (2 folders) (Box 174)
    - Nitrogen progress report, 1970 (Box 174)
    - Nuclear power plant safety (Box 174)
      - University of Minnesota, 1969 (Box 174)
      - Vermont, 1968 (Box 174)
      - Wildlife, 1971 (Box 174)
    - Nuclear testing and radiation, 1962-1964, undated (Box 174)
    - Origin of life, 1965, (2 folders) (Box 174)
    - "Our Explosive Planet," 1966 (Box 175)
    - Population, 1968-circa 1970, (2 folders) (Box 175)
    - Power consumption and human welfare, 1971, (2 folders) (Box 175)
    - Radioactive fallout, Bauer symposium, 1967 (Box 175)
    - Resources for the future, 1971, (2 folders) (Box 176)
    - River research project, 1967 (Box 176)
    - Science and public affairs, undated (Box 176)
    - Science and social issues, commencement address, Grinnell College, Grinnell, Iowa, 1968 (Box 176)
    - "Science and Survival," 1966 (Box 176)
    - Science and technological interventions into nature, Wenner-Gren conference at Burg Wartenstein Conference Center, Austria, 1968 (Box 176)
    - "Science and the Race Problem," 1963 (Box 177)
    - "Science, Technology, and Human Values," Ball State, Muncie, Ind., 1968 (Box 177)
    - Social significance of environmental pollution, 1969 (Box 177)
    - Teach-ins on the environment, 1970, undated (Box 177)
    - "Technology: How Far Can We Trust It?" 1968 (Box 177)
    - Tobacco mosaic virus, 1962-1965, undated, (2 folders) (Box 177)
    - Tobacco mosaic virus, 1962-1965, undated, (3 folders) (Box 178)
    - Tobacco mosaic virus and RNA, 1966, (2 folders) (Box 178)
    - "A Turning Point in the Human Habitation of the Earth," New York Times Magazine, 1966 (Box 178)
    - "A Turning Point in the Human Habitation of the Earth," New York Times Magazine, 1966 (Box 179)
    - Vietnam herbicide program, 1968 (Box 179)
  - Field Enterprises World Book Encyclopedia (Box 164)
    - 1967-1968, (2 folders) (Box 164)
    - 1969-1970, 1975, (2 folders) (Box 165)
    - 1970-1974, (4 folders) (Box 163)
  - Invitations declined or cancelled
    - 1964-1966, speaking invitations and article requests declined, (4 folders) (Box 165)
    - 1967-1968, speaking invitations and article requests declined, (6 folders) (Box 166)
    - 1968-1971, speaking invitations and article requests declined, (2 folders) (Box 167)
    - 1970, speaking invitations, (5 folders) (Box 55)
    - 1970, speaking invitations, (5 folders) (Box 56)
    - 1970, article and book requests declined, (2 folders) (Box 57)
    - 1971, speaking invitations, (2 folders) (Box 57)
    - 1972, speaking invitations, (4 folders) (Box 63)
    - 1972-1977, speaking invitations, (8 folders) (Box 64)
    - 1973, speaking invitations, (5 folders) (Box 58)
    - 1974, speaking invitations, (5 folders) (Box 59)
    - 1974, article requests declined (Box 59)
    - 1974, films and tapings declined (Box 59)
    - 1975, speaking invitations, (3 folders) (Box 60)
    - 1975, article and interview requests declined (Box 60)
    - 1975, advisory board and committee invitations declined (Box 60)
    - 1976, speaking invitations, (2 folders) (Box 60)
    - 1976, speaking invitations, (6 folders) (Box 61)
    - 1976, advisory board and committee invitations declined (Box 62)
    - 1976, articles and interviews declined (Box 62)
    - 1977, speaking invitations, (5 folders) (Box 62)
    - 1977, article and interview requests declined, (2 folders) (Box 63)
  - Manuscripts reviewed (Box 164)
    - 1964-1971, (5 folders) (Box 164)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 163)
  - Newsletters and journals
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science, Science Education News, 1971-1972 (Box 126)
    - Americans for a New America, New Analyst, 1966-1968 (Box 127)
    - Campus Dialogue, 1966 (Box 127)
    - Canadian Council of Resource Ministers, 1969-1971 (Box 126)
    - Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, Change, 1965 (Box 127)
    - Chemosphere, 1971-1972 (Box 162)
    - Collegiate Challenge, 1965-1966 (Box 127)
    - Environmental Bulletin, 1965-1966 (Box 127)
    - "Free Radicals Research Newsletter," 1957-1959 (Box 127)
    - National Academy of Sciences, 1969-1972 (Box 125)
    - National Air Conservation Commission, 1970-1971 (Box 125)
    - National Committee for a Sane Nuclear Policy, 1958-1963 (Box 127)
    - National Committee for an Effective Congress, 1971 (Box 125)
    - National Society for Medical Research, 1970-1972 (Box 125)
    - "Newsman's Gadfly," 1965 (Box 127)
    - Oceanic Foundation, 1968-1972 (Box 125)
    - Rodale's Environment Action Bulletin, 1970-1972 (Box 126)
    - Rodale's Health Bulletin, 1965-1972 (Box 126)
    - Soap and Detergent Association, 1971-1972 (Box 127)
    - Society for Social Responsibility in Science, 1957-1971, (2 folders) (Box 127)
    - Society for Social Responsibility in Science, 1963-1972 (Box 126)
    - Soil Association, 1967-1971, (2 folders) (Box 126)
    - United Church of Christ, Council for Higher Education, 1966 (Box 127)
    - World Federation of Scientific Workers, 1971 (Box 126)
  - Publishers' catalogues and correspondence, 1975-1976
    - A- H, (9 folders) (Box 160)
    - I- R, (8 folders) (Box 161)
    - S-W, (6 folders) (Box 162)
  - Reports
    - Center for the Biology of Natural Systems, agriculture reports, 1973-1977, (3 folders) (Box 94)
    - "The Integrity of Science," American Association for the Advancement of Science (Box 89)
      - Drafts, 1962-1964, (4 folders) (Box 89)
      - Miscellany, 1962-1965, (2 folders) (Box 89)
    - National Science Foundation report on nitrogen and nitrate consumption, circa 1971, (10 folders) (Box 90)
    - Research projects and proposals, 1968-1970, undated (Box 88)
- Correspondence, 1956-1977 (Box 179-205)
  Professional correspondence, received and sent, including some drafts of outgoing correspondence.
  Material types include correspondence with occasional attachments of printed matter.
  Arranged alphabetically by correspondent and chronologically by year therein, with outgoing drafts at the end.
  - A, 1958-1970, (13 folders) (Box 179)
  - A, 1971-1976, (8 folders) (Box 180)
  - B, 1958-1967, (7 folders) (Box 180)
  - B, 1968-1973, (12 folders) (Box 181)
  - B, 1974-1976, (5 folders) (Box 182)
  - C, 1958-1967, (7 folders) (Box 182)
  - C, 1968-1972, (10 folders) (Box 183)
  - C, 1973-1976, (9 folders) (Box 184)
  - D, 1958-1971, (5 folders) (Box 184)
  - D, 1971-1976, (6 folders) (Box 185)
  - E, 1958-1972, (8 folders) (Box 185)
  - E, 1972-1976, (6 folders) (Box 186)
  - F, 1958-1971, (9 folders) (Box 186)
  - F, 1972-1976, (6 folders) (Box 187)
  - G, 1959-1972, (6 folders) (Box 187)
  - G, 1972-1976, (6 folders) (Box 188)
  - H, 1957-1969, (5 folders) (Box 188)
  - H, 1970-1975, (11 folders) (Box 189)
  - H, 1976-1977, (2 folders) (Box 190)
  - I, 1957, 1965-1976, (7 folders) (Box 190)
  - J, 1962-1972, (4 folders) (Box 190)
  - J, 1973-1976, (4 folders) (Box 191)
  - K, 1959-1976, (12 folders) (Box 191)
  - L, 1957-1973, (13 folders) (Box 192)
  - L, 1974-1976, (3 folders) (Box 193)
  - M, 1958-1970, (11 folders) (Box 193)
  - M, 1971-1975, (12 folders) (Box 194)
  - M, 1976, (3 folders) (Box 195)
  - N, 1960-1970, (8 folders) (Box 195)
  - N, 1970-1976, (8 folders) (Box 196)
  - O, 1958-1976, (8 folders) (Box 196)
  - P, 1956-1976, 1956-1974; (12 folders) (Box 197)
  - Q, 1970-1974 (Box 197)
  - R, 1957-1974, (13 folders) (Box 198)
  - R, 1975-1976, (2 folders) (Box 199)
  - S, 1958-1969, (8 folders) (Box 199)
  - S, 1969-1972, (11 folders) (Box 200)
  - S, 1973-1976, (10 folders) (Box 201)
  - T, 1958-1967, (2 folders) (Box 201)
  - T, 1968-1976, (6 folders) (Box 202)
  - U, 1964-1976, (5 folders) (Box 202)
  - V, 1963-1970, (2 folders) (Box 202)
  - V, 1971-1976, (3 folders) (Box 203)
  - W, 1957-1971, (8 folders) (Box 203)
  - W, 1971-1976, (10 folders) (Box 204)
  - X-Y-Z, 1957-1976, (4 folders) (Box 205)
  - Outgoing drafts, 1965-1968, undated, (5 folders) (Box 205)
- Subject File, 1915-1978 (Box 205-321)
  The Subject File contains material identified by topic, personal name, material type, or name of organization. (Note that select organization files are in the Organizations series.) Major topics include biology and botany, civil defense, ecology, environmental pollution, energy, genetics, Italy’s dioxin accident at Seveso, nuclear technologies, peaceful uses of atomic energy, population growth, radiation and radioactive fallout, and the Vietnam War. Margaret Mead, Ralph Nader, Linus Pauling, and Albert Szent-Gyorgi have files in this series. Among the many organizations represented are the United States Office of Naval Research and the U.S. Atomic Energy Commission.
  Material types include correspondence, reports, printed matter, news clippings, research notes, files of published scientific articles, and research notebooks.
  Arranged alphabetically by topic, name of individual, material type, or name of organization.
  - Abbott Laboratories electron spin resonance program, 1964-1965, (2 folders) (Box 205)
  - Advisory Council on Environmental Education, 1968-1972, (4 folders) (Box 206)
  - Agriculture, 1944, 1959, 1969-1974, (2 folders) (Box 206)
  - American Association of University Professors, 1952-1966, (3 folders) (Box 207)
  - American Cancer Society, 1949-1956, (3 folders) (Box 207)
  - American Cancer Society, 1949-1956, (2 folders) (Box 208)
  - American Chemical Society, 1972 (Box 208)
  - American College Health Association, 1969-1970 (Box 208)
  - American Institute of Biological Scientists, 1961-1969, (3 folders) (Box 208)
  - American Institute of Biological Scientists, 1961-1969, (2 folders) (Box 209)
  - American Journal of Botany, 1948-1954 (Box 209)
  - American Naturalist, 1955-1961 (Box 209)
  - American Society of Biological Chemists, 1956-1964, 1971-1973, 1960-1964, 1971-1973 (Box 209)
  - American Society of Plant Physiologists, 1951-1958 (Box 209)
  - Animal research, 1964-1970 (Box 209)
  - Antiballistic missiles, 1967-1970 (Box 209)
  - Archives of Biochemistry and Biophysics, 1949-1962 (Box 209)
  - Argonne National Laboratory, Argonne, Ill., 1964-1966 (Box 209)
  - Arms control and disarmament, 1957-1963, 1969 (Box 209)
  - Articles by Barry Commoner (Box 209)
    - 1937-1951 (Box 209)
    - 1952-1973, (6 folders) (Box 210)
  - Ascorbic acid, 1970, undated (Box 210)
  - Association of New York Scientists, 1947-1949 (Box 210)
  - Autograph requests, 1970-1971 (Box 211)
  - Automobiles and air pollution, 1967-1971, (2 folders) (Box 211)
  - Basic and applied research, 1966-1967, (2 folders) (Box 211)
  - Bateson, Gregory, and the University of Hawaii, Honolulu, Hawaii, 1969-1970 (Box 211)
  - "BHS," scientific articles, 1947, 1958, undated (Box 211)
  - Bibliographies, 1969-1970 (Box 211)
  - Biographical material, 1957-1970 (Box 212)
  - Biological and chemical warfare, 1960-1970, (2 folders) (Box 212)
  - Biology research proposal evaluations, 1957-1961 (Box 212)
  - Biomedical research (Box 212)
    - General, 1971-1974 (Box 212)
    - Lasker, Mary H., 1973-1974 (Box 212)
  - Bionics, 1937,1952, 1960-1963, (3 folders) (Box 212)
  - Bioprotein report presented to North Vietnam Embassy in Rome, Italy, 1974-1975 (Box 213)
  - Botanical Society of America, 1947-1956 (Box 213)
  - British Association for the Advancement of Science, 1971 (Box 213)
  - Bronk, Burt V., proposal for an institute, circa 1965 (Box 213)
  - Cabin plan, 1966 (Box 213)
  - Cancer, 1934-1972, (5 folders) (Box 213)
  - Center for Defense Information, Washington, D.C., 1975-1976 (Box 214)
  - Centrifuge runs, 1963 (Box 214)
  - Chemistry, 1967 (Box 214)
  - Citizens for Survival, 1970 (Box 214)
  - Civil defense (Box 214)
    - Disaster effects, 1960-1961 (Box 214)
    - Miscellany, 1958-1969 (Box 214)
    - Pamphlets, 1953-1963 (Box 214)
    - Shelter program, 1961-1967, (2 folders) (Box 214)
    - Shelter program, 1961-1967 (Box 215)
  - Civil rights, 1963-1967 (Box 215)
  - Climate and weather, 1952, 1965-1971 (Box 215)
  - Coalition for the Environment, St. Louis, Mo., 1969-1970, (2 folders) (Box 215)
  - The Columbia Forum, 1972-1973 (Box 215)
  - Commission on Undergraduate Education in the Biological Sciences, 1964-1966 (Box 215)
  - Commerce Department Secretary's advisory council (Box 215)
    - 1976, (2 folders) (Box 215)
    - 1976-1977, (3 folders) (Box 216)
  - Committee invitations declined, 1969-1971 (Box 216)
  - Committee of One Thousand, 1948 (Box 216)
  - Community Resources, St. Louis, Mo., 1964, undated (Box 216)
  - Conferences and symposia, 1966-1973 (Box 216)
  - Congressional hearings, 1957-1960 (Box 216)
  - Consumer protection and environmental health service, 1968-1970 (Box 216)
  - Cooper, Joseph D., 1966 (Box 216)
  - Council on Economic Priorities, Washington, D.C. (Box 216)
    - 1970 (Box 216)
    - 1970-1972, (2 folders) (Box 217)
  - Cousins, Norman, 1958-1963 (Box 217)
  - Danielli, James, 1950-1958, 1965 (Box 217)
  - Detergents, 1961-1971, (3 folders) (Box 217)
  - Detergents, 1970-1971, undated (Box 218)
  - Differentiation, 1936-1959, (4 folders) (Box 218)
  - Ditchley Foundation Conference on Environmental Control, 1970 (Box 218)
  - Drug Research Reports, 1971-1972, (2 folders) (Box 219)
  - Ecological Society of America, 1970-1971 (Box 219)
  - Ecology (Box 219)
    - Economics, 1961-1971, (3 folders) (Box 219)
    - General, 1967-1970 (Box 219)
    - International development, 1968-1970, (3 folders) (Box 220)
    - Letters from the public requesting information, 1970-1973 (Box 220)
  - Education (Box 220)
    - Adult Education Association, 1955-1956 (Box 220)
    - Council for Basic Education, 1956-1958 (Box 220)
    - General, 1954-1969, undated (Box 220)